# **Erin Van Brunt**

Eugene, OR • (541) 543-4781 • Email Linkedin • Github • Portfolio

### Front-end Software Developer

Full-stack software engineering graduate with an emphasis on front-end user design. Devoted to creating user friendly, sleek, streamline products.

Titled a "unicorn," with a background in hospitality management, the tech industry & a dedicated artist.

Most previously, managed restaurants prioritizing excellence in high-end customer relationships, human resources, marketing, collaborating & team building. Often running & training front-house-house teams of up to 15 people.

Prior to that worked as a Layout Engineer for integrated circuit's in both analog & digital devices. This career required meeting deadlines under strict time constraints in a fast paced work environment, staying abreast with current technological trends, & collaborating with teams of up to 20 engineers from other fields.

For years in my free time I have created books of watercolor, ceramic sculptures & have mastered many instruments.

#### Skills

Full Stack, Javascript, Typescript, Ruby, Rails, Python, HTML5, CSS3, API, RESTful Routing, MVC Framework, JSON, React.js, Axios, Fetch, Active Record, Sinatra, VScode, MongoDB, Structured Query Language, PostgresSQL, B-crypt, Authorization, Node.js, Next.js, Heroku, Netlify, Git/Github, User Interface Design, Operational Analysis, Database Management, MacOS, Windows, Visual Studio Code

## **Projects**

#### Jungle Tetris | July 2022

A single player, multi-level, keyboard input vintage arcade game that uses **React**, **JavaScript** & **Custom Hooks** to generate & manage many geometric shapes called "tetrominoes". The game is managed by game-state stored in **redux**, nested arrays, controllers, dynamic renderings. Containing grid blocks & **CSS** grids, animation, & flex-box.

Github | Video Walk Through | Code Walk Through

#### The Castle Shop | January 2022

E-commerce application built using **MVC Framework**, **Ruby on Rails** for database management, as well as **User Authentication**. With a **React** front-end with fetches data across multiple accounts. User is able to see their previous purchases, as well as other user's purchased castles via a manufactured back-end table associations, engaging through foreign keys, with many-to-many / one-to-many relationships. Other tech used: **JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Gemfile, Node.js, Sinatra, Postgres SQL, Fetch** <u>Github | Video Walk Through</u>

- Fabricated migrations, seeds, database calls & tables in rake console terminal.
- Operated JSON Web Tokens & B-crypt Authenticate to safely store user's data.
- Coordinated & controlled all Github merges & merge conflicts. This produced code that was highly legible for all 3 students in the project. Orchestrated product management, through agile software development.

#### Tic Tac Toe | June 2022

Single player, purely front-end **React JSX** game using **Javascript Logic**. Complete with innovative **CSS** styling, lifted state to track user's place in game & save user's winnings in a way that the data persists in a **SQL** database. Utilized React's **useState** & **useEffect** to control game state. Built links & page state using **React-Router-Dom** & **useHistory**.

Github | Video Walk Through

## **Professional Experience**

#### Restaurant Manager | April 2014 - March 2020

Alamo Draft House, San Antonio, TX | Persephone, Aptos, CA | Mazzi's, Eugene, OR

- After only 6 months at first hospitality position I was moved into management.
- Led the front of house team of 15 employees, practicing open-mindedness & teamwork in my leadership role. Serving 150 300 customers daily.
- Responsible for training, organizing, supervising & evaluating staff, enabling them to maintain excellent customer experience & keep the restaurant running smoothly.
- Handled writing schedules, updated social media, completed weekly stocking product orders & stayed up to date on book keeping, in order to certify the restaurant was in working order, correctly advertised & was financially successful.
- Hired staff that had the correct certifications & knowledge of the competitive trade, brought a level of professionalism, inspiration & dependability to the environment.

#### Layout Engineer | February 2011 - March 2015

Analog Devices | San Jose, CA

- Yielded analog & digital layout designs for integrated circuits in mobile phones.
- Being very passion filled & detail oriented, I worked closely with employees from all departments to ensure we came out with the best product.
- Created & refined a high quality product that brought costs down, ran functionally & established the product & layouts were dry & concise.
- Projects had strict deadlines of 6-8 months, with teams of 10-20 engineers from other departments to deliver MVP.
- Ability to develop & iterate on ideas / concepts through creativity in problem solving & the capability to think outside of established solutions.

### **Education**

Flatiron, Denver, CO: Full Stack Software Engineering Live 2022 General Assembly, SEA, WA: Software Engineering Immersive 2021

Silicon Design Institute, Santa Clara, CA: Mask Design / Layout Engineer 2011-2013

P.C.C., Portland, OR: Art / Math Major 2009-2011

Cabrillo College, Aptos, CA: Art History Major 2007-2009 Harbor High School, Santa Cruz, CA: Class of 2007